Jay Oliver

Alpharetta, GA 30022 | 303-591-1796 | jay@joliver.dev | Github | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack software developer experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in computer and cellphone repair. A quick learner and creative thinker, possessing strong problem solving skills. These skills should prove advantageous in software development for many different industries. Passionate about the future of software development in opening fields.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, Vue, Unity, Web Extensions, Node, Microsoldering, Apple and Samsung repair certified.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

inContext - Github | Demo

Chrome Extension to easily highlight, save, and share webpages.

- Utilized Content Scripts to mark up pages and apply changes to site on load
- Saved content selected to users Google sync account
- Integrated Google People API to retrieve users contacts for site sharing
- Implemented Vue for popup to allow easy navigation of extensions menus and google contacts
- Deployed Node with Express backend to manage message passing

Ohm Logger- Github | Demo

Web app to track daily meditation sessions.

- Implemented isonwebtoken in a node express backend to protect user data
- Built a react frontend with a timer that logged meditation sessions
- Displayed user data on a progressive calendar

Goldfish Timer- Github | Download

Chrome Extension to keep track of time without leaving the page you are on.

- Used vanilla javascript to build popup and backend for a persistent timer
- Pair coded entire application with teammate utilizing effective teamwork methods
- Built a timer with Javascript that displays time in the correct format

EXPERIENCE

AsurionLead Technical Consultant

Marietta, GA - Thornton, CO

04/2017 - 02/2020

- Oversaw daily operation of cellphone repair department, servicing 250+ customers per week
- Consistently received a 97% customer service satisfaction rating, contributing to a top 1% ranking store out of 250 locations
- Supervised 5 technicians, coordinating monthly schedule, and shared valued input during interview processes
- Maintained and streamlined inventory or 20,000 parts, bi-monthly, led to faster service, higher customer retention rates, and 10% more accuracy during auditing shifts.

In & Out Smart Repair

Marietta, GA

Cellphone Technician

07/2016 - 04/2017

- Diagnosed all repairs at drop off, gave accurate repair times based on the repair, and performed repairs within that window, increasing customer retention and satisfaction with a solid repair experience.
- Floated between stores ensuring adequate staffing in all locations during high traffic periods.
- Performed opening/closing duties including depositing cashier funds on a daily basis.
- Acted as store manager during owner's extended LOA, allowing the store to remain open and profitable for a period
 of 4 months.
- Implemented variable pricing model based on inventory levels to achieve maximum profitability.

NanoLumens

Fulton, GA 05/2015 - 07/2015

Sales Engineer Intern

Built a VR application to show clients NanoLumens display in their own office environment.

Assembled and maintained flexible digital signage displays in the company showroom.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School